# Benjamin Maccini

I'm a Texan and a programmer with experience in startups, early-stage product development, algorithms and machine learning. I have spent time in the restaurant industry, local food systems and in retail. Food and food-related technologies are my passion.

benjaminmaccini@gmail.com

+15127053797

github.com/benjaminmaccini

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### unPLUG Dining

Founding Engineer Nov 2021 - Dec 2023

- unPLUG is a Chicago-based tech company developing an omnichannel, data-driven, digital software platform that automates, personalizes, and optimizes the dining experience for enterprise restaurant chains.
- Served as the primary contact for developer relations for our integration partners.
- Managed the onboarding and coordination of new integrations spanning from cloud payments to loyalty platforms.
- · Helped grow engineering team headcount to 12+, brought on numerous advisors and specialists.
- Established our engineering process and culture from both an operational perspective and a technical one through the usage of CI/CD pipelines, Agile practices, and document-driven design.
- Wrote well-tested (>90% coverage), client-agnostic, RESTful platform APIs utilizing modern Python.
- Stood up our cloud infrastructure on AWS through the usage of Terraform and managed GitOps workflows.
- Implemented recommender algorithms with customer-defined business rules and managed inference generation.

#### **Live Oak Data LLC**

Owner May 2021 - Nov 2021

- Live Oak Data is a boutique data labeling service. We curated high accuracy datasets for human-in-the-loop machine learning.
- Solo entrepreneur; performed sales outreach, contractor management, price modeling, and set business objectives

#### **Pensa Systems**

Software Engineer Jun 2019 - Jun 2020

- Pensa Systems is a retail technology company, providing meaningful insights into current shelf conditions using computer vision and machine learning.
- Created diagnostic tooling for runtime object localization services
- Evaluated and QA'd deep learning models for information retrieval and object categorization.
- Implemented a custom 3D scene reconstruction algorithm
- · Productionized research-oriented Python code, effectively eliminating runtime failure

Intern/Contractor Feb 2018 - Jun 2019

- Led the coordination of independent contractors for the purpose of data collection and data labelling
- Engaged in field operations for experimental hardware trials

## EDUCATION

#### **University of Texas at Austin**

B.S. in Mathematics, Minor in Business

May 2019

#### SKILLS

- Services [AWS, CircleCl, Github, Terraform Cloud, PostgreSQL]
- Languages [Modern Python, Go, HCL, SQL]
- Methodologies [REST, Microservices, AGILE, TDD, OKRs, OOP, FP]
- Domain Knowledge [Ordering systems, Payments, Loyalty programs, Hierarchical data modeling, Data labeling services, Retail inventory systems]
- Other skills [Cooking, Non-profit food access at farmers markets, General knowledge of rigging systems and rope work, Working knowledge in Latin American Spanish]